<resources>
<!--
    AirCasting - Share your Air!
    Copyright (C) 2011-2012 HabitatMap, Inc.

    This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
    it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
    the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
    (at your option) any later version.

    This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
    GNU General Public License for more details.

    You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
    along with this program.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.

    You can contact the authors by email at <info@habitatmap.org>
-->
    <string name="about_description">About AirCasting</string>
    <string name="about_description_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            AirCasting is a platform for recording, mapping, and sharing environmental
            data using your smartphone. Currently, AirCasters can upload sound level data recorded by their phone’s
            microphone. AirCasting is intended for measuring outdoor noise. Soon, we’ll expand the range of devices that
            plug into the AirCasting platform to include sound level meters and pollution sensors.
        </p>

        <p>
            Each AirCasting session lets you capture real-world measurements, annotate the data to tell your story, and
            share it with a local and world-wide community via the CrowdMap. What was conjecture based on casual observation
            now becomes a measurable fact. For example, you might think: “This noisy neighborhood is disrupting my sleep.”
            Use AirCasting to identify the factual cause: “The twelve noise spikes greater than 65 decibels between 2am and
            6am significantly degraded my quality of sleep.” When you share your AirCasting data with other AirCasters, your
            data and notes become a social statement, linking your experiences to the community’s observations.
        </p>

        <p>
            We began AirCasting by measuring sound levels in New York City for three reasons:
            <br/>
            1) New Yorkers care about neighborhood noise; it’s the #1 complaint filed with the City’s 311 hotline.
            <br/>
            2) Unwanted noise negatively impacts people’s health.
            <br/>
            3) Smartphones already have microphones, so no additional hardware is required.
        </p>

        <p>
            Start measuring the air in your environment. What will you discover? What stories will you tell with AirCasting?
            Where’s the noisy corner or quiet sanctuary in your neighborhood? Together, with AirCasting, we can better
            understand and improve our environment.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_best_practices">Sound recording best practices</string>
    <string name="about_best_practices_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Follow the Sound Recording Best Practices guide if you intend to contribute your session to the AirCasting
            CrowdMap. If you’re not contributing your session to the CrowdMap, feel free to use AirCasting as you like.
            When recording sound level readings...
        </p>
        <p>
            <b>Do:</b> measure outside, hold phone steady, talk quietly, walk quietly,
            <a href="http://www.takingspace.org/craft-a-windscreen-for-your-phone-mic/">craft a windscreen</a>
            for your microphone (if possible)
        </p>
        <p>
            <b>Don’t:</b> measure inside, put phone in pocket, talk loudly, walk loudly, expose your microphone to wind
        </p>
        <p>
            Do you have an external sound level meter? Compare its readings with those from AirCasting to calibrate
            AirCasting. Under “settings”, adjust the “microphone maximum” until the readings on your phone match those from
            the external sound level meter. Then email us at <a href="mailto:info@habitatmap.org">info@habitatmap.org</a>
            so we can add your phone to our microphone maximum database. To see a partial list of microphone maximums
            for different Android phones,
            <a href="http://www.takingspace.org/set-your-mic-max-to-record-accurate-sound-level-readings/">visit our blog</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
            We welcome input for improving the Sound Recording Best Practices guide. Send feedback to
            <a href="mailto:info@habitatmap.org">info@habitatmap.org</a>.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_start">Start AirCasting</string>
    <string name="about_start_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Make sure your GPS is on and your location on the map is accurate. Press the bullseye button to refresh your
            location and center the map. Don’t see any buttons? Just tap the screen once and they’ll appear; tap the screen
            again to make them disappear. When your location is accurate, press the “play” button to begin an AirCasting
            session.
        </p>
        <p>
            First time? It’s a good idea to review the Sound Recording Best Practices guide before you start.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_view_data">View the AirCasting Data</string>
    <string name="about_view_data_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            AirCasting displays data with three views: the Route Map, the CrowdMap, and the Graph. Toggle between the views by
            tapping the triangular buttons located on the left and right sides of the screen. If you don’t see any buttons tap
            the screen once to make them appear; tap the screen again to make them disappear.
        </p>
        <p>
            The Route Map displays your current position as a colored dot with a white outline; dots without an outline are past
            readings. A dot’s color corresponds to the reading’s intensity at a location. Refer to the “Heat Legend ” (the
            colored bar at the top of the screen) to identify the intensity range for a reading. For example, a yellow dot
            corresponds to a sound level reading between 61 and 70 decibels.
        </p>
        <p>
            The CrowdMap displays AirCasting data from all contributors. Each square’s color corresponds to the average
            intensity of all the readings recorded in that area. Refer to the “Heat Legend ” (the colored bar at the top of the
            screen) to identify the intensity range for a square. For example, an orange square corresponds to an average sound
            level between 71 and 80 decibels. If no colors are displayed, there is no data in that area. The CrowdMap might load
            slowly.
        </p>
        <p>
            The Graph displays your sound level readings over time. Zoom in and out for more or less detail, respectively. Swipe
            to pan through the data.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_note">Make a Note or Share a Reading</string>
    <string name="about_note_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Tap the “share” button to add a note to a specific location or share your readings. The default message includes
            the peak and average decibel levels recorded over the last ten seconds.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_stop">Stop AirCasting</string>
    <string name="about_stop_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Press the “stop” button to end your session. Enter a title, tags, and description and press “Save session”.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_contribute">Contribute to the CrowdMap</string>
    <string name="about_contribute_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            If you save a session, you can also contribute it to the CrowdMap. Sessions added to the CrowdMap are publicly
            accessible. Only press “yes” to contribute your session if it occurred outdoors and you made every effort to
            minimize interferences. Interference factors include wind on the microphone, clothing rubbing against the
            microphone, and loud conversation from the AirCasters. For more information, please review the Sound Recording Best
            Practices guide.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_view_sessions">View Completed Sessions</string>
    <string name="about_view_sessions_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Go to the “Sessions” screen and select a session to view.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_open_session">Share, Edit, or Delete Sessions</string>
    <string name="about_open_session_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Long press a past session to share, edit, or delete it. While viewing a session, share or edit it by pressing
            the corresponding buttons. You can share sessions as a web link or a CSV file.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_heat_legend">Adjust the Heat Legend Units</string>
    <string name="about_heat_legend_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Adjust the relationship between sound levels and display colors by either tapping the Heat Legend at the top of
            the screen or selecting it from the “Settings” screen.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_adjust_microphone">Adjust the Microphone Maximum</string>
    <string name="about_adjust_microphone_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Adjust the microphone maximum by navigating to the “Settings” screen. For most phones the microphone maximum is
            between 80 and 100 decibels. If you have access to a sound level meter, compare the readings with those from your
            phone, and then adjust the “microphone maximum” until the readings on your phone match those from the sound level
            meter.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_profile">Create a Profile or Sign in</string>
    <string name="about_profile_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            You must be signed in to save and contribute your AirCasting sessions to the CrowdMap. Create a profile or sign
            in from the Settings screen.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_limitations">Limitations</string>
    <string name="about_limitations_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Sound level readings recorded by phone microphones may not always be accurate. In addition, AirCasters might
            contribute data to the AirCasting platform without following the Sound Recording Best Practices Guide. In the near
            term, we will work to increase the accuracy of the underlying data by improving the Sound Recording Best Practices
            Guide, creating mapping filters that can segregate and display data from selected AirCasters only, adjusting the
            default “microphone maximum” setting in the app to match the specifications of the Android device on which it is
            installed, and further developing the AirCasting app to receive data from sound level meters.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_health_effects">Health Effects of Noise Pollution</string>
    <string name="about_health_effects_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Noise is a major environmental issue, affecting large numbers of people, particularly in urban areas. Evidence from
            large-scale epidemiological studies links exposure to unwanted environmental noise with adverse health effects.
            Effects include cardiovascular disease, cognitive impairment, sleep disturbance, and tinnitus. Environmental noise
            should be viewed as a public health concern, not just as a nuisance. For more information on the health impacts of
            unwanted noise, visit the <a href="http://www.epa.gov/air/noise.html">Environmental Protection Agency’s website</a>, or read
            this report recently published by the World Health Organization:
            <a href="http://www.euro.who.int/en/what-we-publish/abstracts/burden-of-disease-from-environmental-noise.-quantification-of-healthy-life-years-lost-in-europe">
            “Burden of disease from environmental noise”</a>.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_habitat_map">AirCasting is a HabitatMap Project</string>
    <string name="about_habitat_map_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            HabitatMap is a non-profit environmental health justice organization whose goal is to raise awareness about the
            impact the environment has on human health. We build tools to support grassroots environmental organizing,
            including <a href="http://habitatmap.org">HabitatMap.org</a> - our community mapping platform - and AirCasting.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_open_source">Open Source</string>
    <string name="about_open_source_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            AirCasting is an open source project. You can access the code repositories for the
            <a href="https://github.com/LunarLogicPolska/AirCastingAndroidClient">AirCasting Android app</a> and the
            <a href="https://github.com/LunarLogicPolska/AirCasting">AirCasting web app</a>
            through GitHub.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_thanks">Thanks!</string>
    <string name="about_thanks_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            To <a href="http://www.lunarlogicpolska.com">Lunar Logic Polska</a> for programming the AirCasting website and Android app, to
            <a href="http://www.sonomatech.com/staff.cfm?uemployeeid=8">Tim Dye</a> for big ideas and constructive feedback, to
            <a href="http://www.bsing.net">Brooke Singer</a> for helping steer the project in the right direction.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_funders">Funders</string>
    <string name="about_funders_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Start-up funding for AirCasting was provided by a Google Earth Outreach Developer Grant from the Google Inc.
            Charitable Giving Fund of Tides Foundation. The New York Community Trust has committed to fund additional
            development of the AirCasting platform through a partnership between HabitatMap, the New York Hall of Science, and
            the Hive Learning Network NYC.
        </p>
        <p>
            Built initially as a pavilion for the 1964 World\'s Fair, the New York Hall of Science is now New York City\'s
            hands-on science and technology center. Since 1986, NYSCI has served over seven million children, parents and
            teachers. NYSCI\'s mission is to convey the excitement and understanding of science and technology to children,
            families, teachers and others by galvanizing their curiosity and offering them creative, participatory ways to
            learn. NYSCI features the largest collection of hands-on science exhibits in New York City. Visitors of all ages
            can explore over 450 interactive exhibits.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_feedback">Have Questions or Feedback?</string>
    <string name="about_feedback_content">
        <![CDATA[
        <p>
            Contact us via email: <a href="mailto:info@habitatmap.org">info@habitatmap.org</a>, or call: 347.410.9499.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="about_version">Version</string>
</resources>